software.com 2004-12-04

# Openwave - Legal - Openwave Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy statement describes our practices regarding how personal information we collect on the Openwave web site is used and shared with third parties. By visiting the Openwave web site or otherwise submitting your personal information to us, you accept the practices described in this statement. The information that we receive through our web site depends on what you do during your visit, and what service(s) you request. 

YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO OPENWAVE'S PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED BY OPENWAVE IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AND IN THE UNITED STATES. UNITED STATES LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY. 

IF YOU REPRESENT AN ORGANIZATION, YOU WILL ENSURE THAT EACH MEMBER OF YOUR ORGANIZATION (INCLUDING EMPLOYEES AND CONTRACTORS) ABOUT WHOM PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROVIDED TO OPENWAVE HAS GIVEN HIS OR HER EXPRESS CONSENT TO OPENWAVE'S PROCESSING OF SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION. 

We may ask you to submit personal information at various places on our web site, including on pages for requesting a service or information, subscribing to a newsletter, placing an order, downloading software, submitting feedback, or participating in a forum or survey. This personal information, which you voluntarily submit, may include your name, address, email address and telephone number, as well as other information about, for example, your interest in Openwave products and services, your employer, and your employment position. 

We use this personal information to contact you or send you information you have requested or that we feel will be of interest to you. We may contact you via phone, email, or postal mail. We generally provide an option for you to choose not to receive these types of communications. However, even if you request not to be contacted by us, we reserve the right to use your contact information if we consider it necessary to send you crucial information about, for example, the product or services you have purchased from us or information about changes to our privacy policy. 

We may also collect information automatically about the use of our web site, through, for example, "cookies" or "IP addresses." This information is not collected and stored in a personally identifiable manner, however. This information helps us evaluate and improve our site and is also used for marketing and investment analysis. We may share this information with third parties, but only in aggregate statistical form that includes no personally identifying information. 

"Cookies" are small files web sites place on your hard drive that allow sites to identify you. The use of cookies is a common practice on many web sites. For example, if you allow a site to remember your login name or password, the site places a cookie on your computer. Cookies cannot read any other information on your hard drive. We may place cookies on your computer to allow us to identify you. We may use cookies to measure web site traffic, to offer you certain services, or to customize your visit. However, if you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified of when they are placed, your browser may permit you to do so. An "IP address" is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases your IP address stays the same from browser session to browser session; but if you use a consumer internet access provider, your IP address probably varies from session to session. 

Openwave uses third parties (including contractors and service providers) to help with certain aspects of its operations, which may require disclosure of your personal information to them. For example, Openwave may use a third party to communicate with you (via telephone, email, or letter) about our products or services, to send information to you, to process and collect payment via your credit card (if applicable), to host our web site and related databases, and to perform other work that we may need to outsource. Openwave requires these third parties to use your personal information only as necessary to perform the services they are asked to perform. 

Our web site offers developer forums and message boards. Please be advised that any information posted in these venues will be publicly available. 

We may share some or all of your personal information with any current or future "affiliate" (which means a parent company, a subsidiary, joint venture, or other company under a common control with Openwave), in which case we will require the affiliate to honor this privacy policy. If another company acquires Openwave (or a business unit of Openwave that uses your personal information), that company will possess the personal information collected by Openwave and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this privacy policy. 

We take reasonable steps to protect the personal information you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure. However, you should know that no company, including Openwave, can fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information. 

Your privacy is very important to us. Due to factors beyond our control, however, we cannot fully ensure that your personal information will not be disclosed to other third parties. For example, we may be legally required to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. 

Our site may link to other sites not controlled by Openwave. We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of any other web sites. We therefore encourage you to read the privacy policies on those other sites. 

We may amend this privacy policy at any time by, in our discretion, either: (1) sending you a notice of the amended policy to the email address you have submitted to us (if applicable), in which case you agree to the amended version if you do not contact us to inform us otherwise, or (2) posting the amended version on our web site, in which case you agree to the amended version if you continue to use the web site. 

If you have a question or comment about the Openwave site or a request to correct or delete your personal information, please send it to us by using our web site Feedback form. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to fulfill your request in a timely manner. However, even if Openwave deletes such personal information from its 'live' database(s), it may still be stored on other databases (including those kept for archival purposes). 

The materials on this site are provided by Openwave Systems Inc. ("Openwave") for informational purposes only. By downloading any material from the site, you agree to our Terms and Conditions. 

Last modified July 15, 2004

|  |  | | Related Links  
---|---  
   
| | Terms & Conditions  
Read the Terms and Conditions of using the Openwave site.   
| | Trademarks  
A listing of Openwave's Trademarks and Service Marks.  
| | Contact Us
